# DAIZE DONG

 ♠ Personal Page
 Image: Google Scholar
 Image: Google Scholar

#### Summary

I am a graduate in Computer Science & Mathematics and Applied Mathematics from UESTC, now spending my gap year in Shanghai AI Lab and Westlake University. I am dedicated to uncovering the intrinsic properties of neural networks with theoretical guarantees, aiming to develop robust and effective AI systems. My research interests primarily revolve around:

- 1. Representation capabilities of neural networks (e.g. interpretability, robustness, sparsity, etc.).
- 2. Fundamental structural designs of neural networks regarding efficiency and effectiveness (e.g. MoE, GNN).
- 3. Applications of artificial intelligence in the development of scientific research (e.g. AI for physics, biology, psychology, etc.).

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Electronic Science and Technology of China

Sep. 2019 – Jul. 2023

Bachelor of Computer Science & Mathematics and Applied Mathematics

GPA: 3.91/4.00

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# OpenGVLab, Shanghai Artificial Intelligence Laboratory

Jul. 2023 – Present

Research Assistant

Instructor: Dr. Xiaoye Qu. Supervisor: Prof. Yu Cheng

Mixture of Experts, Large Language Models, Natural Language Processing

- Explored the structures of Large Language Models (LLMs) and efficient properties of Mixture of Experts (MoE).
- Conducted research on effective strategies to for incorporating MoE structures into pre-trained dense Large Language Models.

# Center for Artificial Intelligence Research and Innovation, Westlake University

Apr. 2023 – Present

Research Assistant

Collaborator: Zhangyang Gao. Supervisor: Prof. Stan Z. Li

Molecular Generation, AI for Drug Discovery and Development

- Explored the strategies for 2D and 3D molecular representation learning and generation.
- Conducted research on the unified molecular modelling framework using pure transformers.

# Data Intelligence Group, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China

Jul. 2022 – Mar. 2023

Research Intern

Instructor: Prof. Wen Li

Domain Adaptation, Transfer Learning

- Explored the theories and algorithms for unsupervised and self-supervised learning.
- Conducted research on knowledge transfer strategies for Multi-Target Domain Adaptation (MTDA).

#### NLP Group, JD Explore Academy

Feb. 2022 - Oct. 2022

Independent Collaborator

Instructor: Dr. Liang Ding. Supervisor: Prof. Dacheng Tao

Sparse Training, Model Compression, Natural Language Understanding

- Explored parameter-efficient strategies for downstream fine-tuning.
- Conducted research on efficient dynamic neural networks in Computer Vision (CV) and Natural Language Processing (NLP).

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### 1. A Graph is Worth K Words: Euclideanizing Graph using Pure Transformer. [Paper]

Zhangyang Gao\*, **Daize Dong**\*, Cheng Tan, Jun Xia, Bozhen Hu, Stan Z. Li. *The 41st International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2024).* 

# 2. iDAT: inverse Distillation Adapter-Tuning. [Paper]

Jiacheng Ruan, Jingsheng Gao, Mingye Xie, **Daize Dong**, Suncheng Xiang, Ting Liu, Yuzhuo Fu 2024 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME 2024). **(Oral)** 

# 3. PAD-Net: An Efficient Framework for Dynamic Networks. [Paper]

Shwai He, Liang Ding, **Daize Dong**, Boan Liu, Fuqiang Yu, Dacheng Tao.

Proceedings of The 61st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2023).

<sup>\*</sup> Equal Contribution

4. SparseAdapter: An Easy Approach for Improving the Parameter-Efficiency of Adapters. [Paper]

Shwai He, Liang Ding, Daize Dong, Miao Zhang, Dacheng Tao.

Findings of The 2022 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP 2022).

5. SD-Conv: Towards the Parameter-Efficiency of Dynamic Convolution. [Paper]

Shwai He, Chenbo Jiang, Daize Dong, Liang Ding.

IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision, 2023 (WACV 2023)

#### **PREPRINTS**

1. Blending and Aggregating the Target for Blended-Target Domain Adaptation.

Tong Chu, **Daize Dong**, Jinhong Deng, Lixin Duan, Wen Li. *Under Review by IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (IEEE-TIP).* 

#### **PROJECTS**

# LLaMA-MoE: Building Mixture-of-Experts from LLaMA with Continual Pre-training. [Code]

Jul. 2023 - Dec. 2023

- Conducted research on the framework to integrate the mixture-of-experts (MoE) structure into existing LLMs.
- Explored multiple methods to initialize the converted MoE model using pretrained parameters from the LLM.
- Proposed a novel random split strategy with output-scaling to recover model performance.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Natural Languages: English (TOEFL 100), Mandarian.

**Programming Languages:** Python, C/C++, Java, Matlab, etc.

Deep Learning Tools: PyTorch, Hugging-Face Transformers, Torch-Lightning, DeepSpeed, etc.

# Relevant Courses

**Deep Learning:** Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning for Computer Vision, Deep Learning for Natural Language Processing, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Data Mining and Big Data Analysis.

Optimization Algorithm: Optimization Theory and Methods, Introduction to Algorithms.

**Mathematics:** Differential Calculus, Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, Stochastic Process, Discrete Mathematics, Graph Theory, Multivariate Statistical Analysis, Causal Inference.

**Computer Science:** Computer Organization and Architecture, Compiler Principles, Computer Operating Systems, Database Principles and Applications, Information Retrieval, Software Engineering.